freeride.com 2018-12-09

# Privacy policy - Freeride

## INTRODUCTION

We at Freeride AB protect you as a visitor and member, which means, among other things, that we handle your personal information in a manner that takes into account your integrity. This Privacy Policy describes the personal information we collect from you through our interactions with you and how we use these data. The Privacy Policy also describes your rights to us and how you can assert your rights.

All processing carried out by Freeride AB takes place in accordance with the application of data protection legislation. Within the EU / EEA, from May 2018, the Data Protection Regulation (DGPR) Data Protection Regulation applies.

You can always contact us if you have questions about privacy and processing of personal data by sending an email to:

info@freeride.com  
Our website address is: https://www.freeride.com.

## **WHAT IS A PERSONAL TASK?**

All types of information directly or indirectly attributable to you as an individual are counted as personal data according to the Personal Data Act. Examples of such information are name, address, phone number, e-mail address, contest contribution, use of our websites or IP address.

## WHAT PERSONAL DATA WE COLLECT AND WHY WE COLLECT THEM

We use personal data to conduct our business and deliver the products and services we provide. We also use the information to create a better experience when visiting the website, as well as informing you about your account and products. In addition, we use personal information for marketing activities and to show more relevant ads.

Freeride AB processes personal information in order to provide relevant content on the website www.freeride.se, for example. to ensure that content on the website is presented effectively on your device according to your wishes. The processing is necessary to meet our and your legitimate interest in providing information and services on the website.

We receive certain personal information directly from you, for example, when you create a member account, subscribe to a newsletter, sign up for an event or participate in a contest. We collect some of your personal data by registering how you interact with our website, for example, using technology like cookies.

Sometimes we also collect personal data from third parties. Examples of third-party sources, which may vary over time, are payment transaction providers, service providers who provide data to allow us to customize our internet marketing, as well as partners we collaborate to arrange events.

### RECIPIENTS OF PERSONAL DATA AND REASONS FOR SHARING YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION

We will not sell or rent your personal information to other companies. We transfer to, or share your personal information with, selected recipients if necessary for the purpose for which the information has been collected, for example, to provide a product or service that you have requested.

Personal Data Advisers are companies that process personal data on our behalf and on our instructions. These companies must comply with our security requirements in terms of technical and organizational measures associated with processing and are not permitted to use personal data for other purposes. We also transfer your personal data with companies or authorities that are independent personally responsible, that is to say, determine the purpose and means of processing your personal data. When your personal information is shared with a company or authority that is an independent personally responsible person, their privacy policy applies.

### COMMENTS

When visitors leave comments on the site, we collect the information shown in the comment form as well as the visitor’s ip address and user agent string to help detect junk messages.

  * All information collected through the use of cookies is anonymous.
  * IP addresses are stored for security purposes.
  * Email addresses are treated with strict privacy and are only used for newsletters (optional) and administrative communications.
  * Non-public user information is considered secret. However, the police and other Swedish authorities may request logs and other data in criminal investigations.
  * Members do not have to enter their real name but can choose to be completely anonymous.

### ANALYSIS

We use Google Analytic for traffic analysis to analyze repeatedly known visitors.

### COOKIES

If you leave a comment on our site, you can choose to save your email address in cookie files. This is for your convenience because you do not have to fill in these information again the next time you write a comment. These cookie files are valid for a year.

### EMBEDDED CONTENT FROM OTHER SITES

Articles on this site may contain embedded content (such as video clips, images, articles, etc.). Embedded content from other sites behaves exactly the same as if the visitor has visited the other site.

These sites can collect information about you, use cookie files, embed additional third-party tracking and monitor your interaction with said embedded content, including tracking your interaction with this embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to the site in question.

## WHO WE SHARE YOUR DATA WITH

Freeride AB shares your personal information with suppliers or subcontractors to fulfill agreements with you and for other purposes as set out in this privacy policy. We share your personal information with companies that help us with marketing and IT services. We also hire companies to provide delivery of products that need access to personal data in order to provide these services, for example, when a prize is posted after a member competition.We may also provide personal information to the authorities if we are required to do so by law.

## HOW LONG WE KEEP YOUR DATA

We save your personal information in a form that allows identification of you only for the purpose of the treatment.We process and save your personal information as long as it is necessary to fulfill our agreed commitments to you.We also save your personal information for other purposes, such as accounting, fraud prevention or money laundering. For this purpose, personal data is stored for as long as is necessary for the purpose or required by applicable law.

If you comment, the comment and its metadata will be saved without time limit. The reason for this is that we need to be able to find and approve follow-up comments automatically and not put them in queue for review.

For users who register on your site (if any), we also save the personal information they provide in their user profile.All users can view, edit or delete their personal information at any time. Even the site’s administrators can view and edit this information.

## WHAT RIGHTS DO YOU HAVE ON YOUR DATA?

If you have an account or have written comments on this site, you can request an export file containing the personal information we have about you, including any information you have given us. You may also request that we remove any personal information we have about you. This does not include any data we have to save for administrative, legal or security purposes.

You may access all of your personal data collected by Freeride AB by contacting us by e-mail or the address contained in the Contact Us section below. You who have a member account can also review and edit many of the personal information you provided to us directly in your account on the website.

## WHERE DO WE SEND YOUR INFORMATION?

Comments from visitors may be checked via an automated spam detection service. In case of suspected crime, personal data may be sent to authorities if we are required to do so by law.

## MORE INFORMATION

### HOW WE PROTECT YOUR INFORMATION

Freeride AB has taken all reasonable technical and organizational security measures required to protect personal data against unauthorized access, loss, change and destruction. However, there is always a risk of disclosing personal information over the internet. No technology system is completely protected from intrusion.

We use full SSL / HTTPS on all our websites. This encrypts our user communication with the servers so that personally identifiable information is never caught by third parties without permission.  
In case of a violation, system administrators immediately go through the affected users and try to reset the password if necessary after informing the user.

### WHAT PROCEDURES DO WE HAVE FOR DATA SHEETS

We are constantly working to ensure our systems and eliminate the risk of leaks. Should anything happen, however, this will immediately be notified to the Data Inspectorate under GDPR.

### FROM WHICH THIRD PARTIES WE RECEIVE DATA

We do not accept data about third-party users.

### WHAT AUTOMATED DECISION MAKING AND / OR PROFILE CREATION WE DO WITH OUR USER INFORMATION

We do not use any service for automated decision making.

### INDUSTRY REQUIREMENTS FOR INFORMATION SERVICE

We do not appear in a regulated industry where we are subject to additional privacy laws.

## CONTACT US

Freeride AB with organization number 556663-4753 and the address Bastugatan 41, 118 25 Stockholm, is responsible for the processing of your personal data. We comply with Swedish data protection legislation.Comments or questions regarding this Privacy Policy or questions regarding Freeride AB’s processing of your personal information can be sent to:

Freeride AB  
Bastugatan 41  
118 25 Stockholm

_Privacy Policy was updated by 2018-05-23_
